Abdullah Waseem

Personal details



Abdullah Waseem



abdullahwaseem948@gmail.



+923313232552



paf colony zarrar shaheed road Lahore cantt, house no 163-B 54810 Lahore



221.120.222.1:9292 221.120.222.1: 9696



linkedIn. com/in/abdullah413084

Skills

Google BigQuery && Google Cloud Platform (GCP)



CSS, HTML, JavaScript



GIT

Airflow



Python && SQL



Looker Studio && Power



AWS (Amazon Web Services)



Languages

English



Urdu



Licenses & certifications

Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere

Summary

Experienced data engineer, data analyst and front-end developer with a passion for building user-friendly, efficient and scalable applications. Strong skills in data modeling, ETL processes, data warehousing, data visualization, data cleaning techniques and front-end development. A good learner, team player and always up to date with the latest trends and technology.

Education

ICS

Mar 2015 - Mar 2017

Forman Christian College, Pakistan (Lahore)

Computer Engirineeng

Sep 2017 - Jul 2021

COMSATS University Islamabad, Pakistan (Lahore)

Employment

Data Engineer

Nov 2022 - Present

Adara, Inc., Remote

- Knowledge of AWS Command Line Interface (CLI), AWS Identity and Access Management (AWS IAM), AWS Glue, Amazon Athena, Amazon S3, Amazon QuickSight, AWS Lambda and AWS CloudFormation, Data Warehousing · Amazon Redshift.
- Knowledge of Data lake CLI and Data lake Console, Amazon API Gateway (Data lake Respectful API), Amazon Cognito, Lambda functions.
- Worked on collecting ETL Requirements and developed ETL jobs to build a data warehouse and Worked on ELT process.
- Performed analytics on data in data Warehouse (Big Query) and Worked on Data lake (Google cloud Bucket).
- Developed Looker studio resorts and created a business dashboards in React/Next JS.
- Worked on complex SQL query writings.
- Created a ETL tools and Automation by using Python.
- Integrated Google analytics and GTM with multiple websites.

Associate Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Nov 2022

InfoTech Group, Lahore

Project (Orange Train Website):

- Managing large and complex projects or multiple components with smooth implementation and testing of application.
- Designed and developed base classes, framework classes and re-usable components.
- Experience in using React JS components, Forms, Events, Hooks, Keys, Router, plus Redux, Animations and Flux concept and used rest APIs.

Project (Docyard):

- Lazy Loading Modules and Auth Guard.
- Generic Components and Services.
- Experience with creating custom directives, decorators, and services to interface with both restful and SOA services.
- Experience with RESTful APIs and database integration.
- Knowledge of front-end testing frameworks like Jasmine.
- Good understanding of Git, Agile development methodologies.